okay so uh uh shall we start
it
microphone so actually
that
um until the mid time or until this
lecture the the I apologize you know
putting a lot of pressure for equations
and so on the uh that is kind of
important part but at the same time I
know that this is you know a little bit
complicated but from now on from today
uh to the rest of the lecture it's more
for the uh the uh the play with the
neuron network engineering so we still
have some Mass but the the portion of
the mass is quite
smaller uh so I just want to uh mention
it and
the uh
today the
uh
uh I will discuss about the search uh
which we actually explain a little bit
in the uh V algorithm but this V
algorithm search was actually not the
real search that we are usually conduct
for speech condition and this one is
quite more the difficult part and I I
will try to explain about the
search in the intuitive Manner and again
this is a simple part of the explanation
the real search happened in ASR is more
complicated and
the
um usually the it's nowadays that speech
becomes very simple but it used to be
very complicated like a P structure the
context
dependency context dependency with some
clustering hidden Mark of model
Le and complicated anram so this sear
part used to be very complicated uh but
the today's part is little bit
simplified version it's actually end to
end method the simplify the search part
as well and the then uh the if I have
more time I will also explain about the
uh
representation of the uh the hypothesis
uh in speech condition which is very
important in many application so I will
explain about the NS 3 ltis and the last
one again if I have a time I will also
explain about the system combination uh
this is also quite often used in speech
recognition and then today we will
release the coding
assignment okay so uh the today's
actually part it's either hmm or the end
to end especially
CTC uh or attention based the
approaches uh we explained about the I
explained about the almost all component
feature extraction acoustic model
lexicon language modeling part right and
the same for the end to end part the CTC
and so on I still don't really explain
about the the neuron Network
architecture and so on but some kind of
high level concept I already explained
about it and what I that mostly try to
explain about you is actually how to uh
derive this PW given
LA and then we use you know this the
compos form or we use a CTC or atten
then so
on but this is actually not the end of
the speech condition as you see from
this equation we have another important
component this is this ARX
part this part is actually not very not
easy or I say it is one of the most
difficult part uh and this is a today's
topic okay so uh let's uh first uh the
uh try to understand this the arax
part let's say this is a token sequence
and this is the the uh possibly all
possible uh the token
sequencies and then uh the if for
example we have a vocabulary size and
having the length of J and so on
actually this such space become super
huge uh just like this is by the way
very small cases only 5,000
vocabulary our usual conversation we use
the uh the uh 20 to uh the the the 100
depending on the uh our definition using
the word or using the uh the sub word
but 5,000 is actually smaller side
and then the lus is 20 this is actually
a little bit longer sentence but then
the uh this number uh becomes the too
large uh to consider all possible
sequence during the
search so search is all similar to the
the other kind of issue in the summation
over the sequence we always have to
consider this kind of the quite large
number of other the hypothesis and then
try to find the best one and the uh this
is one
example uh the used inure
of let's say the uh the Leng is
three uh the token length is three and
then vocabulary is only three and then
uh the uh I will move to the sh
quiz can you open
I think the question is how
many sequences how many hypothesis for
this particular cases we have to
consider
uh and then uh let's talk about the
greedy search which we already uh maybe
I should we say answer because
everyone's correct so I don't have to
say right 27
right three times three * three right
just
expanding and as you see this is very
redundant so we could actually try to
kind of find the the better way uh the
better strategy to the the prun the
hypothesis and one of the the hypothesis
is is the garch which I already
introduced in the B algorithm but anyway
you know uh we just you know find out
the the the locally the best passes and
then continue to do that uh so this is
actually at a very shallow computational
cost uh it is
the the way to avoid the the
uh it is way to avoid the
the um the computational large
computational cost but as you see once
we have an error in the kind of a early
stage uh we cannot uh recover the error
from this so uh this the gitty SE is
actually the most simple but the most ER
method by the way in the CTC actually
the gitty is often used because it
doesn't have any the token dependency
explicitly so it's actually a reasonable
assumption to to perform the uh the the
the gitty recording uh in CTC if we
don't have a uh the the any kind of
language models and so on also the model
is getting powerful and then the garch
is actually not very bad so this is also
the one important uh the
not however if we consider the RN
transducer or attention based ASR or
once we try to consider the language
model and so on we actually have to
consider the token dependency and then
we actually have to consider the entire
history so in this case we
couldn't the the consider this beam
search a GRE search is Val and we have
to consider other types of the search
and then uh that we introduce a beam
search uh which is to limit the number
of the hypothesis for every other for
every time frame uh for example I use
the N uh for the the number beam and in
the
uh in the uh the previous example uh if
you're using the beam search in the
every time
uh for example if n equal two we always
try to keep the two best
hypothesis first part is actually easy
uh from among three we just getting the
two okay but second part is actually not
very easy each of the hypothesis would
have a kind of a different kind of a
node right so we first actually expand
this one expand in this side as well
and then among actually this the six
pattern we can get the two so originally
it was the originally in the first step
only the three to get the two but if we
expand the next time frame and then it
becomes actually little bit larger due
to the kind of expansion and considering
the the the list of the
hypothesis but after that that we
actually performing this kind of process
the the the recursivity and then getting
the two the possibly the best the beam
sech result uh and then from this final
two result uh we can check the score and
then getting the one the best one so
this is actually the beam search the
algorithm and this is also a way to kind
of the escape the heavy
computation and the uh compared with G
research this actually becomes little
bit more computational cost uh the uh
because of the various actually the the
the hypothesis that we have to consider
but still uh it's not like the the
exponential so by doing that the beam
search is actually quite
reasonable okay so this is kind of
the um
comparison of the beam search and the
greedy the de coding and as you see that
the beam search the keeping the
hypothesis more and then possibly have a
more uh the the the the accurate result
and of course if beam be one it's go to
Grey
recording and if beam becomes the the
the
infinite and then or vocabulary size and
then it becomes the uh the the uh the
consider the hood search so that we
should be careful about not beam to make
the beam to be very but the beam search
is also not perfect again uh so the the
um but the uh there are several other
method like a sampling and so on but for
speech recogition uh beam s is the most
the widely used uh the the
approach and I just kind of writing
the
um the beam
search uh the algorithm with some
equations so again that the first part
uh we have a the N
hypothesis H sorry not the vocabulary
size which I defined as the
uh I think I didn't Define yeah just
kind of uh
the the vocab let's say vocabulary size
I didn't set
it the variable so first part is that
among the vocabulary size we sort it and
then getting the two best or any best
hypothesis and the next one is actually
given this kind of a
two each of the kind of the node we
expand hypothesis so it becomes actually
two times vocabulary size as a
space and then uh we actually sorting it
and then we get the kind of best the two
best other
example and then continue this kind of
approaches so important oper ation is
keeping the
hypothesis and getting the score for
among all hypothesis and then sorting to
get the top end so this the operation is
the important for the beam search okay
so uh the uh the main equations uh is as
I mentioned the the uh preparing the
hypothesis
getting the score for each
hypothesis and the sort up to one to n
and the S is kind of I believe you guys
understand it and the score uh what the
kind of score uh we would use and then
uh we use the uh PW given
go that can be computed by the uh the
hmm
Theon and the uh
uh or the CTC or transor or attention
based the
approach and then uh the uh based on
this score that we can uh actually get
the uh the uh the the best the
hypothesis and so on by the way this
score part is actually generally the O
extended
uh for example uh this uh the score uh
would be actually the combined by the
language model score obtained from the
external uh the the uh the
models uh or we can even combine the two
algorithm like attention the CTC and so
on or attention or RN transer and so on
we also have some kind of H IC
penalty uh if we want to make the kind
of a the the uh the hypothesis to be
shorter then that we actually are making
a penalty not to make that kind of a
score to be uh the uh the longer uh by
just the adding the minus lengths or
something like that in the score uh so
this are the huge part the beam search
is quite often happened uh so this is
also just a one note but that is a kind
of quite common way to actually using
the various kind of information
source and then in this cases in the
fusion cases uh we also often the
combine when we combine we also have to
kind of care about the the weight and so
on like whether we should kind of more
on the the speech recognition score or
whether we should score R more on the
language model score and so on that can
be also generally
balanced okay so this is a kind of the
beam search that I
explained however I didn't explain about
the the the important part of beam
search the uh the which is I for example
I mentioned here
that J = 3 or J = 20 the kind of fix the
lens of the
token however is this
true no right given the speech we don't
know how many LS of the token how many
word we actually Ed so this is actually
one part of the search so in addition to
this search we actually have to consider
when this kind of graph expansion would
be stopped so actually in including this
part uh the such space again becomes
very
huge and then uh the uh there are the
the lot of kind of ways to uh getting
the the end of the the position in the
search but one approach to stop the
search is to actually including the end
of sentence
symbol as a part of our kind of a
prediction so for example one of this
kind of a token like ABC sorry it can be
smaller but it is ABC ABC and so on but
let's say B is end of sentence and uh
this is a
model actually predicting this one and
then we can actually consider the stop
of
the hypothesis and so on so some of the
cases for example if uh B is end of
sentence
okay and in this cases this one is B
here apologize it is too small but could
guess that ABC ABC ABC ABC okay so
second part is always B so this part is
end of
sentence
um not a good way so I will try to kind
of make it larger
not the but I guess now ABC is bit
visible right and if B is the end of the
sentence
token and then this sentence is stopped
here and then uh this case is actually
this sentence is stopped here so we
don't have to actually expand this
one and this case is this senten is
STP to in this kind of the step but
other talken like a a a a a a c a a a c
until they actually predicting the B
it's actually continue to grow so we
still need to actually uh the uh the set
some kind of
Maximum uh the ls that we want to kind
of search them and then uh we continue
this beam
search and the actually stuck the
hypothesis that reaches to the
B and then keeping it in the the the the
our kind of a
stock and until we kind of reaching to
some kind of a threshold let's say we
keep to the work on this kind of
expansion until 10 and then we kind of
checking the kind of
the stock that are reaching to the end
of sentence and then the finally sorting
and then getting the the best one so
this is actually the the more exact way
of how to also including the uh the uh
the way to kind of the search the lenss
in the beam
search yeah it's the set kind of limit
to 10 and so on so in this case is the
finite but the it's possibly it can be
actually growing to the the infinite yes
but and that solution might exist but as
a kind beam search actually having a lot
of
htic including this beam withs and the
maximum length and so on is also another
other one which is you know to set a
kind of a reasonable lengths usually we
set this kind of the maximum lengths uh
proportional to the input lengths so
this kind of Maximum lengths is actually
reasonable but by setting this one and
then uh the uh the among this kind of
the expansion we usually get the kind of
list of the the sentences that goes to
the end of sentence
yeah um again beam such has a lot of
htics it's a very good question so
actually uh the uh yeah I can expand
your question uh even my explanation
actually didn't explain anything about
input right input Lings I only mentioned
about output Lings right uh that uh that
is actually called the uh output
synchronous uh beam
search and this output synchronous beam
search is what I explained it's very
intuitive because this is you know
output is one to J token and then we
expand it to the kind of each of the
token and so on however uh our speech
also has another time right which is
input time and this is very different so
actually the output synchronous beam
search is only the of used for the
attention based the ASR which actually
by using the the soft attention to
consider all
possible the information in the time as
a weighted sum as a result model
actually doesn't have our information
about time uh input time stamp and then
there the people are using output
synchronous beam search which I
explained here and actually this is also
again uh attention based enod deoda has
this kind of form and then just chain
rule to decompose it and then the there
is no kind of other uh the explicit time
information because it
is the the the cross attention the
across the time to the marginalize this
information so in this case the out out
put synchronous beam search is
fine however we also have a lot of the
example in the uh uh the the uh the uh
the for the hmm CTC and the RN trans is
actually similar to CTC uh in some kind
of a form so I actually want to explain
uh this part with the the CTC hmm and
addn transmisser
they are using the input synchronous uh
beam
search and then uh the uh the in this
case uh input time frame is more
important uh to do the beam search uh
than the the output synchronous beam
search and then the one important
difference uh would be that in the input
synchronous beam search uh if we
reaching to the end of the time and then
we actually can stop the uh the uh beam
s so there is no kind of a issue for the
the Endo problem uh and so on but the
let's discuss about the input
synchronous beam such bit more so first
uh the the this are kind of a recap
review of our kind of a the problem so
CTC or hmm or RN transer R trans is a
little bit different so maybe I can
discuss about CTC and this can be also
applied but uh we usually have the token
sequence W which that we have discussed
on the output synchronous beam search
but we also have additional uh the the
the variable which is alignment of the
SE
right and there are two differences
I should make it as a
question I I hope you guys can already
understand it but it's already written
so uh one difference is of course length
right output and the input is are always
different unfortunately that is a
problem in speech and makes it very
difficult and another difference is that
uh in the CTC cases in addition to the
original token vocabulary we also have
the blank symbol right and in the hmm
cases it's this one becomes p and this
one becomes the p and the internal hmm
State as the augmented vocabulary and so
on anyway vocabulary size is different
by considering the duration and the
length the
different and then the how to kind of
the change the previous synchronus the
the the the uh hypothesis expansion to
the time the input
synchronus we actually are using the
Z as a kind of expansion unit so this
one apologize again which can be too
small for the people who sit down in the
the back part uh but the left side is
the Lal synchronus and the uh the output
synchronus and the uh right side is
input synchronous by the way I sometimes
to call output synchronous beam such the
label synchronous beam such and
sometimes I call input synchronous beam
search as the frame synchronous beam
search apologize that this is a more
like other the the terminology that the
generally people using the the speech
coition
but anyway try to be careful about the
terminology so left side is output
synchronous and the right side is uh the
uh the the input synchronous and then uh
the this part uh the I also have the
this the output synchronus we have a
three vocabulary a b c and in the the
input synchronous cases like just kind
of omit C you know since it is too many
if we have a four
so instead we have a and blank so the
vocabulary side is also different in
left side three and right side the the
the A and exclude C but anyway first
expansion is the having the the blank
and let's go expand this one uh
basically same ABC ab b c ABC or AB
Brank AB Brank AB
Brank and then other taking the thir
step it becomes also more uh the
expansion AB blank AB blank AB blank and
so on so it's actually the almost same
as the uh the output synchronous beam
search if using the hard alignment right
but there's some difference and that I
actually want you guys to uh
enjoy by writing this is not by the can
you
yeah
so like the example in the uh light top
corner for each pass uh please F out
the uh hard alignment token and uh
corresponding the token hard alignment
sequence and corresponding token
sequence this is not the test or this is
not the even participation Point uh
and this is example in the uh right top
corner
right so just you know uh using this uh
as a example and try to kind of figure
out all other
part okay maybe
uh some people may finish or some people
may in the middle uh but uh the I I hope
you guys enjoy some quiz of you know the
the using the brain to you know convert
the the many of the patterns of the the
CTC alignment to the uh uh actual token
and then please uh the check the
token sequence
and then the compared with the previous
output uh the
synchron uh what is the
difference the I say that the alignment
part is not different right it's just
expanding uh the uh and it becomes you
know to
27 patterns of the sequence but the
after this it convert to the Token SE
it is definitely the difference right
which what would be the difference yes
there are lot of duplication actually
right any other
different yes LS is very different right
even the last Cas is then is
zero so uh the uh alignment pattern uh
is uh the the has such kind of variation
and which we have to consider during the
beam
search what I mean to say oh yes so the
uh there are lot of uh
uh lot of actually duplicated passes
that's corresponding to the same token
right so we actually have to consider it
and in this case how to do that we just
adding them
uh so that the until this the time the
the probability of for example in this
case the just emitting the a would be
represented as this kind of six pattern
so we just suming all of
them and then uh this actually
computation is very similar to the for
uh computation in CTC uh that we
actually uh learned in the previous
lecture and so on so I sometimes you
continue to use this notation but it is
actually more exactly it is little bit
different because uh the this uh the the
CTC uh the the forward part was actually
the the until large T and we also have a
fixed W right but in this cases
depending on the beam s result this W
also can be changed
uh but I will anyway using this notation
for this other problem and so
on okay so and then uh now we can get
the score for each time
frame so difference is that again each
time frame not in the output now but for
each time frame uh we can actually get
the lot of the sub
sequence like
this so even the length is actually
different and then uh we get the kind of
top
end and then the performing The Beam
search so this is a little bit tricky uh
but this is actually one way to uh Sol
the Ty the input synchronous beam search
but there are lot of variant of the
input synchronous beam search for
example some people actually thinking
that this is not great because the
lengths is different right comparing the
kind of the hypothesis which has a
different thingss of the token is not
very accurate so some people actually
father having applying the humanistics
to solve this issue and so on but the
general basic beam s is like
this okay
uh that's actually the mostly for the
beam search part and then I will give
you some of the the tips uh for uh the
CTC uh beam search because that would be
the one of the uh the coding assignment
uh the the the
question so first part is that I
mentioned that this is a kind of
important score so we just kind of know
adding everything and then even keep the
maintaining this kind of score for each
hypothesis is
important however actually uh it is not
enough we usually actually keeping the
scores uh uh the keeping the kind of two
scores one is
ending at the Brank and the other is
others so the for example
in the case that we are the reaching to
emit the a
token uh blue
one is the finished without
blank and the red one is finished uh
with the
blank and as a kind of a computation
it's better to keep separately are
keeping this kind of
score because if we goes to the t+ one
next
time as you may remember whether this
previous token is be the uh the the
Brank or not uh we can actually uh the
the uh the change the kind
of uh to see next token is repeated
token or not so uh after again you know
after we finish this
part and then next token is a
and then uh if although these kind of
six same token to emit a but if this is
ended with a blank symbol and then next
we come a it becomes a a repeated token
right and if uh not it becomes a
actually it's changing depending on the
previous uh the uh the result of the to
so to deal with this kind of a
relationship uh it's better to keep the
hypothesis of both uh if better to keep
the score of both the non Brank and
Brank are the score in the memory so
this is actually one of the important
tips uh when we actually do the beam
search in
CDC is that clear it a little bit
complicated
but I hope intuitively you understand it
and after that in the algorithm you
could further understand this other part
but at least you know I think you guys
now see that oh yes the
CTC depending on the Brank or not
repeated token Behavior can be changed
so that's actually the the the important
part and then this is the treatment to
deal with
it and the next uh the uh the tip
uh is that what the we have
discussed so now we don't have to care
about the end of
sentence so we just kind of uh the
performing The Beam search until uh the
uh the end of the uh the the speech
frame and then the beam start is gone so
we do not have to think about uh the
setting some kind of a thresholder
or
complicated algorithm to com perform the
uh the uh the end of sentence the
approaches and so
on and we can also by the way adding the
score uh the when uh the language mod
the score uh in the case that the the
Tok uh is uh the the the pry kind of uh
the uh they given um uh so in this cases
for example a Ab the ba each cases we
can actually compute the language model
score as well right and then we actually
can adding them when we performing The
Beam
search okay so that's a kind of a
summary of the beam
search and as I explained there are lot
of
approximation uh the to avoid the all
possible sequence and the beam suches
the one htics end point detection is
another htics and weight during the
score Fusion is
other also the htics and there are many
others if
we consider more efficient Advanced beam
search so that's the the beam search
product any question
okay by the way this one is very
simplified
version very simplified version maybe I
can also explain a little bit I
mentioned that you know we can for
example put the language model score
here but uh if for example this other
part speech Rec ition part is based on
the
character and this part is
W then again the uh the uh the lens
becomes different and then we have to
adjust it and it's actually this kind of
problem happens everywhere uh the in the
the beam search so that actually makes
the beam search very complicated so uh
the my
experience uh the the people uh the
studying the beam search they doing a
research in the beam search usually very
good researcher it's actually first they
know everything for example we have to
know the the everything about the uh the
speech part acoustic modeling part rich
compart and so on and then we also have
to know about other other anram part or
the neural network language modeling
part and then we have to kind of adjust
the things that also requires a deep
knowledge about the the speech
recognition and language modeling and so
on and another part is that a lot of
humanistics so it is not the ideal
because PE the people I as far as I know
again that the people that are very the
the working on the the beam search again
that all of them I met a very great
researchers but some of them are just
simply great researchers know everything
about it and then you know this kind of
algorithm perfectly understand and
having a very kind of efficient
algorithm they came up with uh the other
type is that since there are lot of htic
there are lot of how to say things have
to consider and we have to for example
the consider the balance between the
acoustic model or language model oron or
even the the uh the uh the comp overall
the computation memory and so on a lot
of things we have to consider so this
kind of another type of the great people
working on the beam SE is actually
become a very good manager so in the
management is actually lot of thinking
about a lot of actually consideration of
the lot of you know people's kind of
Health people's performance people's
salary and we all always we have to
consider a lot of kind of other scores
and then hug and then making a good
decision which becomes the the good spe
performance and so on so given my
experience the the people working on the
beam SE is always very good research
some manager and
so okay so
um think I can quickly go through this
part um
first I want to explain about anest
sequence so spe condition is not
actually
perfect and then in this cases as you
see from the beam search
finally uh if we finish the beam search
we actually uh don't have a just one
bested one we just have actually the
several the hypothesis
and then corresponding score so not only
just the the output the one best the ASR
result but it's actually can providing
the
list so uh this is actually uh the uh
the one of the the important cases if we
use the entire this instead of the best
kind of a hypothesis uh why this is
important uh this is because uh the
invest uh the speech is not always
perfect for example this is actually the
I pick up the some of the ASR result and
in this case and I getting it in the
Sorting uh getting the N the the hypoth
ASR hypothesis and the top one is better
so in this cases the successful in terms
of the the top one is actually the
corresponding to the reference gr stes
this are kind of successful cases but
most of the cases it's actually not as
you see that the top hypothesis is
different right which one is the correct
one among
them yes third one yes third one is a
correct one so unfortunately uh they
make some mistakes but if we kind of the
providing the invest it actually has a
the the the correct result
so this kind of information can be used
for many the post processing like
instead of providing the best hypothesis
to the kind of a machine translation we
can providing the best several kind of a
hypothesis and then throw it to the the
machine translation and then in the
machine translation to do the kind of
best the the score we can get and then
providing it and so on with that it
might kind of miate the issue error
issue that potentially happen in the ASR
and so on there are lot of other
application but anyway the the the S is
not perfect uh in this case we all using
this kind of the nest
representation however Nest is not very
efficient
way because for example this are the
three sentences almost same right just
this part is wrong and I go to this
which part yeah this part only this part
and this part is
wrong uh but you know the using this
kind of the representation is not
efficient so uh people actually using
the representation called
ltis uh this is also similar to the so
but by using this latis
representation we can actually compactly
uh represent many of the Hypes so uh
some system is the only supporting the
nest but the other systems also
supporting latis which can provide a
rich information than the nest and so on
and unfortunately espet only support
Nest by the
way okay uh so I think uh that's it for
the uh ltis part and I skip the system
combination and we move to the uh
explanation about the coding assignment